<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Instapaper on adolfo ramírez corona</title>
    <link>https://adolforismos.com/tags/instapaper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Instapaper on adolfo ramírez corona</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-mx</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 15:34:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adolforismos.com/tags/instapaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginner&#39;s Guide to Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/the-beginners-guide-to-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 15:34:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/the-beginners-guide-to-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>«The first effective feedback system is measurement. The things we measure are the things we improve. This holds true for the number of pages we read, the number of pushups we do, the number of sales calls we make, and any other task that is important to us. It is only through measurement that we have any proof of whether we are getting better or worse.»The Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Deliberate Practice January 25, 2017 at 03:34PM via Instapaper http://jamesclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Your Microbiome Wants for Dinner - Issue 31: Stress - Nautilus</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/what-your-microbiome-wants-for-dinner-issue-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 18:02:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/what-your-microbiome-wants-for-dinner-issue-31/</guid>
      <description>«The stomach might better be called a dissolver, the small intestine an absorber, and the colon a transformer. These distinct functions help explain why microbial communities of the stomach, small intestine, and colon are as different from one another as a river and a forest. Just as physical conditions like temperature, moisture, and sun strongly influence the plant and animal communities that one sees on a hike from a mountain peak to the valley below, the same holds true along the length of the digestive tract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could we explain the world without cause and effect?</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/could-we-explain-the-world-without-cause-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 17:18:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/could-we-explain-the-world-without-cause-and/</guid>
      <description>«Hume argued that when we seek causal relations, we can never discover the real power; the, as it were, metaphysical glue that binds events together. All we are able to see are regularities – the ‘constant conjunction’ of certain sorts of observation. He concluded from this that any talk of causal powers is illegitimate. Which is not to say that he was ignorant of the central importance of causal reasoning; indeed, he said that it was only by means of such inferences that we can ‘go beyond the evidence of our memory and senses’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Happiest People Don&#39;t Let Their Minds Wander, According to a Harvard Study</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/the-happiest-people-dont-let-their-minds-wander/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 19:16:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/the-happiest-people-dont-let-their-minds-wander/</guid>
      <description>«A recent Harvard study reveals that stray thoughts and wandering minds are directly related to unhappiness»The Happiest People Don&amp;rsquo;t Let Their Minds Wander, According to a Harvard Study December 21, 2016 at 07:16PM via Instapaper http://www.inc.com/quora/the-happiest-people-dont-let-their-minds-wander-according-to-a-harvard-study.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People with autism make more logical decisions, study suggests</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/people-with-autism-make-more-logical-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 07:51:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/people-with-autism-make-more-logical-decisions/</guid>
      <description>«Our findings add to evidence showing that people with autism think differently to typical people. Although this is related to the difficulties they experience in social situations, this different way of thinking may sometimes be advantageous in situations where it is it better to follow your head and not your heart.»People with autism make more logical decisions, study suggests October 26, 2016 at 07:51AM via Instapaper http://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/autism-make-logical-decisions-gambling-study-a7361046.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuroscience Reveals the Nourishing Benefits That Silence Has on Your Brain</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/neuroscience-reveals-the-nourishing-benefits-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 07:19:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/neuroscience-reveals-the-nourishing-benefits-that/</guid>
      <description>«She found that two hours of silence a day produced new cell creation in the hippocampus, the main part of the brain associated with memory.»Neuroscience Reveals the Nourishing Benefits That Silence Has on Your Brain October 26, 2016 at 07:19AM via Instapaper http://www.inc.com/betsy-mikel/your-brain-benefits-most-when-you-listen-to-absolutely-nothing-science-says.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Your Brain Looks Like When It Solves a Math Problem - NYTimes.com</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/what-your-brain-looks-like-when-it-solves-a-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 07:17:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/what-your-brain-looks-like-when-it-solves-a-math/</guid>
      <description>«The imaging analysis found four stages in all: encoding (downloading), planning (strategizing), solving (performing the math), and responding (typing out an answer).»What Your Brain Looks Like When It Solves a Math Problem - NYTimes.com October 26, 2016 at 07:17AM via Instapaper http://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/29/science/brain-scans-math.html?nytmobile=0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is How To Resist Distraction: 4 Secrets To Remarkable Focus</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/this-is-how-to-resist-distraction-4-secrets-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 15:38:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/this-is-how-to-resist-distraction-4-secrets-to/</guid>
      <description>«Here’s how to resist distraction and be less reactive:
Control your context: You can’t react to what’s not there.
Stay calm: Stress makes you dumb. Stress and reacting leads to dumb behavior.
Think about your goals: Get Stoicism, mindfulness and dopamine on your side.
Make a deliberate decision: When you do, your brain is better able to resist no-no’s.»This Is How To Resist Distraction: 4 Secrets To Remarkable Focus October 11, 2016 at 03:38PM via Instapaper http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreams and revelations</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/dreams-and-revelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 16:15:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/dreams-and-revelations/</guid>
      <description>«Where does all this leave us today? On one hand, the link between REM dreams and spiritual experience disturbs some religious people because they fear it suggests that religion is nothing but delusional dreaming and hallucinations. On the other hand, the connection upsets some die-hard atheists, who dislike the idea that spirituality is rooted in our biology – that it is functional and adaptive, and central to who we are$1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This happiness hack from a wildly popular Stanford class can help you create a life you love</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/this-happiness-hack-from-a-wildly-popular-stanford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 04:10:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/this-happiness-hack-from-a-wildly-popular-stanford/</guid>
      <description>«To get started, we recommend thinking about the last time that you were on cloud 9—an experience that gave you a glimpse of adrenaline-induced ecstasy, if only for a moment»This happiness hack from a wildly popular Stanford class can help you create a life you love September 22, 2016 at 04:10AM via Instapaper http://qz.com/784279/this-happiness-hack-from-a-wildly-popular-stanford-class-can-help-you-create-a-life-you-love/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why One Neuroscientist Started Blasting His Core</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/why-one-neuroscientist-started-blasting-his-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 17:50:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/why-one-neuroscientist-started-blasting-his-core/</guid>
      <description>«neuroscientists showed that they have discovered a discrete, elaborate network in the cerebral cortex that controls the adrenal medulla. It seems that the connections between the brain and the adrenal medulla are much more elaborate than previously understood. Complex networks throughout the primary sensory and motor cortices are tied directly to our stress responses.»Why One Neuroscientist Started Blasting His Core September 11, 2016 at 05:50PM via Instapaper http://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/08/cortical-adrenal-orchestra/496679/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Writing To-Do Lists Helps Your Brain (Whether Or Not You Finish Them)</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/how-writing-to-do-lists-helps-your-brain-whether/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 02:48:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/how-writing-to-do-lists-helps-your-brain-whether/</guid>
      <description>«Keeping a list of tasks you need to perform is like taking notes when you&amp;rsquo;re reading a book or listening to a lecture. When you take notes, you need to filter external information, summarize it in your head, and then write it down. Many studies have shown that note taking helps us distill the information we hear and remember it better than we would if we&amp;rsquo;d just heard or read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S.O.L.I.D: The First 5 Principles of Object Oriented Design</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/solid-the-first-5-principles-of-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 02:46:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/solid-the-first-5-principles-of-object/</guid>
      <description>«S.O.L.I.D stands for:
When expanded the acronyms might seem complicated, but they are pretty simple to grasp$1
S – Single-responsiblity principle O – Open-closed principle L – Liskov substitution principle I – Interface segregation principle D – Dependency Inversion Principle»S.O.L.I.D: The First 5 Principles of Object Oriented Design July 29, 2016 at 02:46AM via Instapaper https://scotch.io/bar-talk/s-o-l-i-d-the-first-five-principles-of-object-oriented-design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex, drugs and late nights: on night owls and psychopaths</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/sex-drugs-and-late-nights-on-night-owls-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 02:40:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/sex-drugs-and-late-nights-on-night-owls-and/</guid>
      <description>«Night owls are quite different from morning larks. Morning people are more punctual, perform better in school, and have higher success in the corporate world. Evening people are more risk-taking, creative, extraverted and have higher alcohol and nicotine consumption. They also have laxer moral standards, and an increased desire for casual sex. Indeed, my colleagues and I suspected that the characteristics of people who habitually lurk in the shadows of the darkness could have a relationship with the ‘Dark Triad’ of personality: Machiavellianism, psychopathy and narcissism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los seis grandes tipos de historias en los que puedes meter todas las novelas - Librópatas</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/los-seis-grandes-tipos-de-historias-en-los-que/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 02:21:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/los-seis-grandes-tipos-de-historias-en-los-que/</guid>
      <description>«¿Cuáles son esos seis formatos? El primero es el de pobreza a la riqueza, esas historias en las que los protagonistas evolucionan para mejorar su posición. Tras este tipo de historias están, en la lista, sus opuestas: de ricos a pobres, o las tragedias, que historias de caídas. El tercer tipo de historias es la que llaman ‘hombre en un agujero’, que empieza con una caída y sigue con una subida$1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models I Find Repeatedly Useful — Medium</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 02:06:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-medium/</guid>
      <description>«A mental model is just a concept you can use to help try to explain things (e.g. Hanlon’s Razor — “never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by carelessness.”). There are tens of thousands of mental models, and every discipline has their own set that you can learn through coursework, mentorship, or first-hand experience.»Mental Models I Find Repeatedly Useful — Medium July 26, 2016 at 02:06AM via Instapaper https://medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falling for sleep</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/falling-for-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 01:57:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/falling-for-sleep/</guid>
      <description>«Medicalisation obscures sleep’s true nature – its breadth and depth and joy. It conceals the personal, transcendent and romantic dimensions of sleep. We are in dire need of restoring our sense of sleep’s mythic dimensions – of reimagining our personal experience of sleep. I believe this can be best accomplished through poetry, spirituality and, ultimately, personal investigation.»Falling for sleep July 26, 2016 at 01:57AM via Instapaper https://aeon.co/essays/the-cure-for-insomnia-is-to-fall-in-love-with-sleep-again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Manifesto Against ‘Parenting’</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/a-manifesto-against-parenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 13:43:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/a-manifesto-against-parenting/</guid>
      <description>«Does this mean that parents don’t matter? To the contrary: From a scientific perspective, being a parent, as opposed to “parenting,” is crucially important, but it’s important in a very different way.»A Manifesto Against ‘Parenting’ July 24, 2016 at 01:43PM via Instapaper http://www.wsj.com/articles/a-manifesto-against-parenting-1467991745</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Great Listeners Actually Do</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/what-great-listeners-actually-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 12:29:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/what-great-listeners-actually-do/</guid>
      <description>«In our experience, most people think good listening comes down to doing three things:
Not talking when others are speaking Letting others know you’re listening through facial expressions and verbal sounds (“Mmm-hmm”) Being able to repeat what others have said, practically word-for-word»What Great Listeners Actually Do July 24, 2016 at 12:29PM via Instapaper https://hbr.org/2016/07/what-great-listeners-actually-do</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If It Doesn’t Suck, It’s Not Worth Doing — The Mission — Medium</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/if-it-doesnt-suck-its-not-worth-doing-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 11:09:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/if-it-doesnt-suck-its-not-worth-doing-the/</guid>
      <description>«in his new book, Ego is the Enemy, Ryan Holiday explains that a primary obstacle to success is the idea of success.»If It Doesn’t Suck, It’s Not Worth Doing — The Mission — Medium July 24, 2016 at 11:09AM via Instapaper https://medium.com/the-mission/if-it-doesnt-suck-it-s-not-worth-doing-1efdc6eb695c</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Narrated Reality</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/adventures-in-narrated-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 10:29:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/adventures-in-narrated-reality/</guid>
      <description>«Nietzsche, who was the first philosopher to use a typewriter, famously wrote “Our writing tools are also working on our thoughts,” which media theorist Friedrich Kittler analyzes in his book Gramophone, Film, Typewriter (p. 200):
“Our writing tools are also working on our thoughts,” Nietzsche wrote. “Technology is entrenched in our history, “ Heidegger said. But the one [Nietzsche] wrote the sentence about the typewriter on a typewriter, the other [Heidegger] described (in a magnificent old German hand) typewriters per se.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Productivity to Workflow Engineering - Study Hacks - Cal Newport</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/from-productivity-to-workflow-engineering-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 15:51:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/from-productivity-to-workflow-engineering-study/</guid>
      <description>«The goal with workflow engineering is not to maximize convenience or to minimize cost and disruption. It is instead to start from a blank slate and ask: “if my goal is X, what is the absolutely most effective way to get there?”»From Productivity to Workflow Engineering - Study Hacks - Cal Newport April 5, 2016 at 03:51PM via Instapaper http://calnewport.com/blog/2016/03/29/from-productivity-to-workflow-engineering/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How People Learn to Become Resilient</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/how-people-learn-to-become-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 15:42:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/how-people-learn-to-become-resilient/</guid>
      <description>«It’s only when you’re faced with obstacles, stress, and other environmental threats that resilience, or the lack of it, emerges: Do you succumb or do you surmount?»How People Learn to Become Resilient March 14, 2016 at 03:42PM via Instapaper http://www.newyorker.com/science/maria-konnikova/the-secret-formula-for-resilience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How People Learn to Become Resilient</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/how-people-learn-to-become-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 10:14:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/how-people-learn-to-become-resilient/</guid>
      <description>«If you are lucky enough to never experience any sort of adversity, we won’t know how resilient you are»How People Learn to Become Resilient March 13, 2016 at 10:14AM via Instapaper http://www.newyorker.com/science/maria-konnikova/the-secret-formula-for-resilience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Does Therapy Work?</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/why-does-therapy-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 17:40:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/why-does-therapy-work/</guid>
      <description>«“Successful therapists learn to be ‘amygdala whisperers’ by leveraging the social brain in order to help clients face their fears,” writes Cozolino.»Why Does Therapy Work? November 12, 2015 at 05:40PM via Instapaper http://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/why_does_therapy_work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is the No. 1 Ritual You Need to Do Every Day</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/this-is-the-no-1-ritual-you-need-to-do-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 15:34:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/this-is-the-no-1-ritual-you-need-to-do-every-day/</guid>
      <description>«Here’s how to use rituals to improve your life:
Savoring Ritual: Make the good times better by having something you do to focus on the good things. Share good news with a partner or have a regular mealtime with your family.
Grief Ritual: When something has you down, write about your feelings. It’ll reduce the pain and help you cope.
Personal Starting Ritual: Beat anxiety and procrastination by having a fun ritual that says it’s time to get to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing the indescribable: Underlying features of reported mystical experiences</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/describing-the-indescribable-underlying-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 22:28:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/describing-the-indescribable-underlying-features/</guid>
      <description>«mystical experiences are associated with alterations in brain areas related to spatial boundaries.»Describing the indescribable: Underlying features of reported mystical experiences October 27, 2015 at 10:20PM via Instapaper http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2015/10/151015141513.htm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Answer? | Hardcore Zen</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/no-answer-hardcore-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 22:59:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/no-answer-hardcore-zen/</guid>
      <description>«Zen teachers who refuse to answer their students’ questions in words are never answering with silence. It’s a way of indicating that life itself is the answer the student is searching for.»No Answer? | Hardcore Zen October 25, 2015 at 10:57PM via Instapaper http://hardcorezen.info/no-answer/4075</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth&#39;s Blog: Simple questions for writers</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/seths-blog-simple-questions-for-writers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 19:49:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/seths-blog-simple-questions-for-writers/</guid>
      <description>«Writing can make a difference. Write to make a difference.»Seth&amp;rsquo;s Blog: Simple questions for writers October 25, 2015 at 07:44PM via Instapaper http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2015/10/simple-questions-for-writers.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation for the People?</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/automation-for-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 22:08:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/automation-for-the-people/</guid>
      <description>«Rather than humanize the machines, we seem intent on making our human institutions more machinelike. Embedded in Silicon Valley’s techno-optimist worldview is a liberta»Automation for the People? October 16, 2015 at 10:08PM via Instapaper http://www.democracyjournal.org/35/automation-for-the-people.php</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host in the Shell</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/host-in-the-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 22:05:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/host-in-the-shell/</guid>
      <description>«The last thing I remember from that lecture in university was my professor saying that three things control your life: your genes, your environment, and luck. “And if you have the choice, take luck,” he said.»Host in the Shell October 16, 2015 at 10:04PM via Instapaper http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/host-in-the-shell/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s ditch the dangerous idea that life is a story</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/lets-ditch-the-dangerous-idea-that-life-is-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 22:30:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/lets-ditch-the-dangerous-idea-that-life-is-a/</guid>
      <description>«But many of us aren’t Narrative in this sense. We’re naturally – deeply – non-Narrative. We’re anti-Narrative by fundamental constitution. It’s not just that the deliverances of memory are, for us, hopelessly piecemeal and disordered, even when we’re trying to remember a temporally extended sequence of events. The point is more general. It concerns all parts of life, life’s ‘great shambles’, in the American novelist Henry James’s expression. This seems a much better characterisation of the large-scale structure of human existence as we find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emotions That Make Us More Creative</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/the-emotions-that-make-us-more-creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 21:15:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/the-emotions-that-make-us-more-creative/</guid>
      <description>«Motivational intensity, they concluded, was a more important variable affecting scope of attention than the mere experience of positive or negative emotions. Presumably, this is because low motivational states facilitate the search for new goals to pursue, whereas high motivational states focus us on completing a specific goal. So next time you want to keep an open mind and see the big picture, it’s probably best if you’re just in a pleasant (or even sad) mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Malpensante</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/el-malpensante/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 09:21:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/el-malpensante/</guid>
      <description>«Quitémosnos las alas y tratemos de escribir con los pies sobre la tierra, ¿sí?»El Malpensante August 26, 2015 at 09:21AM via Instapaper http://elmalpensante.com/articulo/1985/como_escribir_y_como_no_escribir_poesia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurodiversity Rewires Conventional Thinking About Brains</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/neurodiversity-rewires-conventional-thinking-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 17:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/neurodiversity-rewires-conventional-thinking-about/</guid>
      <description>«By autistic standards, the “normal” human brain is easily distractible, is obsessively social, and suffers from a deficit of attention to detail.»Neurodiversity Rewires Conventional Thinking About Brains August 25, 2015 at 05:20PM via Instapaper http://www.wired.com/2013/04/neurodiversity/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dalai Lama’s Daily Routine and Information Diet</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/the-dalai-lamas-daily-routine-and-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:19:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/the-dalai-lamas-daily-routine-and-information/</guid>
      <description>«At the heart of this message is a larger testament to the most essential characteristic of reality — something Alan Watts, who began popularizing Eastern philosophy in the West when the Dalai Lama was still a teenager, captured memorably when he wrote: “Life and Reality are not things you can have for yourself unless you accord them to all others.”»The Dalai Lama’s Daily Routine and Information Diet June 16, 2015 at 05:19PM via Instapaper http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuro Myths: Separating Fact and Fiction in Brain-Based Learning</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/neuro-myths-separating-fact-and-fiction-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:11:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/neuro-myths-separating-fact-and-fiction-in/</guid>
      <description>«Some people are left-brained and some are right-brained. &amp;ldquo;This is total nonsense,&amp;rdquo; says Fischer, &amp;ldquo;unless you&amp;rsquo;ve had half of your brain removed.&amp;rdquo; This may have emerged from a misunderstanding of the split-brain work of Nobel Prize winner Roger Sperry, who noticed differences in the brain when he studied people whose left and right brains had been surgically disconnected.»Neuro Myths: Separating Fact and Fiction in Brain-Based Learning June 16, 2015 at 05:11PM via Instapaper http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>✚ You Have Ideas</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/you-have-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:03:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/you-have-ideas/</guid>
      <description>«What you need is more bad ideas.»✚ You Have Ideas June 16, 2015 at 05:03PM via Instapaper http://shawnblanc.net/2015/06/you-have-ideas/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“How can housework be made into a creative activity?&#34;&#34;</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/how-can-housework-be-made-into-a-creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 18:17:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/how-can-housework-be-made-into-a-creative/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;How can housework be made into a creative activity?
The minute we apply a glimmer of consciousness to a mechanical gesture, or practice phenomenology while polishing a piece of old furniture, we sense new impressions come into being beneath this familiar domestic duty. For consciousness rejuvenates everything, giving a quality of beginning to the most everyday actions.&amp;rdquo; via Instapaper http://www.brainpickings.org/2015/06/01/gaston-bachelard-the-poetics-of-space-housework/ &amp;#8212;http://www.brainpickings.org/2015/06/01/gaston-bachelard-the-poetics-of-space-housework/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>…autists could actually be seeing much deeper into the minds</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/according-to-the-intense-world-theory-autists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 17:55:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/according-to-the-intense-world-theory-autists/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;According to the Intense World Theory, autists could actually be seeing much deeper into the minds, thoughts and emotions of themselves and others, which triggers active avoidance and lock down behaviors. It also requires the ability to simulate others as if you where them and to extrapolate to where their thoughts and behaviors are leading them. Seeing into the minds of others can be extremely disturbing.&amp;rdquo; via Instapaper http://wrongplanet.net/interview-henry-and-kamila-markram-about-the-intense-world-theory-for-autism/&amp;#8212;http://wrongplanet.net/interview-henry-and-kamila-markram-about-the-intense-world-theory-for-autism/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>we must approach our vacations…</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/we-must-approach-our-vacations-with-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 20:09:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/we-must-approach-our-vacations-with-the-same/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;we must approach our vacations with the same tenacity as we do our vocations, and use them to come back to the office better than before.&amp;rdquo; via Instapaper https://hbr.org/2015/06/5-rules-for-a-vacation-thats-truly-worth-it&amp;#8212;https://hbr.org/2015/06/5-rules-for-a-vacation-thats-truly-worth-it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A master in the art of living</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/a-master-in-the-art-of-living-draws-no-sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 20:06:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/a-master-in-the-art-of-living-draws-no-sharp/</guid>
      <description>A master in the art of living draws no sharp distinction between his work and his play; his labor and his leisure; his mind and his body; his education and his recreation. He hardly knows which is which. He simply pursues his vision of excellence through whatever he is doing, and leaves others to determine whether he is working or playing. To himself, he always appears to be doing both.”&amp;rdquo; via Instapaper https://hbr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapping Your Inner Wolf</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/tapping-your-inner-wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 19:31:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/tapping-your-inner-wolf/</guid>
      <description>““The main characteristic of an alpha male wolf,” the veteran wolf researcher Rick McIntyre told me as we were watching gray wolves, “is a quiet confidence, quiet self-assurance. You know what you need to do; you know what’s best for your pack. You lead by example. You’re very comfortable with that. You have a calming effect.”” This “calming effect” reminds me the rain maker story. It is the person who can enable calm in a group who really changes the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savater: “La aflicción es más fuerte que la razón”</title>
      <link>https://adolforismos.com/savater-la-afliccion-es-mas-fuerte-que-la-razon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 18:36:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adolforismos.com/savater-la-afliccion-es-mas-fuerte-que-la-razon/</guid>
      <description>“Cuando Amador vivía conmigo y le reñía me decía: “Y pensar que todos creen que eres un padre modélico”. Yo le decía: “Eh, aquí soy el padre, no el que escribe los libros”.” Esta es una prueba.Savater: “La aflicción es más fuerte que la razón” http://cultura.elpais.com/cultura/2015/05/21/actualidad/1432235116_142670.html June 5, 2015 at 06:35PM via Instapaper</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>